[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 23]
You got here so quickly.
It caught me off guard.
Last time,
weren't you whispering sweet nothings to the fiancée
of the marquis's son?
Why are you
all alone today?
I actually feel a bit sorry for you.
What?
Are you now concerning yourself with
my personal affairs?
It was a joke.
I'm just curious to see
what kind of man could capture Fourth Lady Xie's heart
for secret trysts.
The few ships you intercepted today are
of little consequence to the Canal Gang.
With how ruthlessly you operate,
you'd never leave any loose ends.
So your visit today is
not about the ships.
Take a guess.
What do you think I'm here for?
When Shen Zhibai was falsely accused of major corruption in Hengtang,
it shocked the court and the public.
The late Emperor ordered an investigation.
All officials in Hengtang worked hand in glove
to claim that he was
using anti-corruption efforts as a facade
to pocket public funds,
chief among which was
the embezzlement of canal transport profits.
If you want the truth,
I'm afraid you must
come to this dock.
For a century, your Pei family has monopolized
the profits from Hengtang's canal transport.
If your family hadn't testified,
this false accusation would never
have been pinned on the Shens.
As expected,
you're here to hold my family accountable.
Your family didn't actually conspire with the others,
so you're still redeemable.
I'm here to
find evidence against
the person pulling the strings behind your family.
I can
get you the evidence.
But
it comes with a price.
Give yourself to me.
What do you say?
The largest
Eastern Pearl market in Hengtang
is right ahead.
We'll see
its shopfront sign soon.
♪ I counted every moment ♪
♪ Memories take root; the annual rings grow ♪
♪ Who bore the parting wind ♪
I asked you a question.
♪ And wove it gently into the warmth of the past? ♪
Qingyuan?
♪ I honor every scar upon your hand ♪
Eastern Pearls, right?
♪ Through endless nights, a lone soul wanders this mortal world ♪
There's a shop here.
This shop...
♪ Turning back, we embrace— one fleeting moment of love and hate ♪
Hello. What are you looking for?
Could you
show me
your best Eastern Pearls?
♪ As flowers fall beneath the dusk ♪
They're all here.
Or shall I help you pick some more?
♪ Sorrowed by many a farewell, comforted by sweet memories ♪
I can't just give you
the evidence
you want.
You've been alone for a long time, ♪ One life, one love, one heart devoted to you ♪
so you aren't aware that
in Hengtang, even in the capital,
♪ In the depths of darkness, you are the stars ♪
families rely on marriage alliances to strengthen their power.
♪ Trample the abyss, together we run ♪
I'll help you find the evidence,
and you'll give yourself to me.
♪ May we grow deep in years together, sharing one life and one pillow ♪
It's a reasonable deal.
The Eastern Pearl hairpin from before broke.
I've been wanting to give you a better one,
♪ Rise and fall as one, whether we're united or apart ♪
but I could never find the time,
until today.
♪ Hand in hand, we brave all the storms of life ♪
But I don't think their stuff is good.
Qingyuan,
actually,
♪ Never to part, forevermore ♪
you don't have to rush to fall in love with me.
After we get married,
we'll have 5 years, 10 years,
a lifetime together.
As long as you're willing,
I'll wait for you.
You want to use the case of Shen Zhibai
to implicate Commissioner Hu in the old case of Hengtang.
It is a brilliant move.
This elegant one suits you better.
But I was one step ahead of you.
I've already killed off
all the spineless cowards you could use
as a pawn.
Right now, only I can help you.
Qingyuan,
do you like
this or this?
Either's fine.
Either?
Mom said if you can't choose, the options are all bad.
This won't do.
Let's go to the biggest Eastern Pearl shop!
You're truly a rare breed,
unfazed even by the possibility of the extermination of your clan.
Someone like you
is a worthy opponent.
But I forgot to tell you that
whoever stands in the way of me finding the truth
will only have one end,
which is death.
You must be joking.
In a place like Hengtang,
even an imperial edict
carries little weight.
At best,
incoming officials
end up like Wei Changyan.
At worst, they
become content with playing dumb
like Prefect Qian.
Only Shen Zhibai would be
so ignorant, reckless, and delusional
as to think he could shake the order of Hengtang.
Hengtang has its own rules.
Break the rules,
and the price is death.
That was the case for Shen Zhibai.
And it will be
the case for you.
Well said.
But what is hidden must come to light.
Who knows what the rules will look like
down the road?
In the past,
I only found Fourth Lady fascinating.
But now it seems
you're even more interesting.
This matter is too shocking, scandalous,
and unheard of.
Forgive me, but I can't agree.
We're both mothers.
I don't believe
you don't know
who is genuinely good to your child.
Qingyuan is great
and Chunzhi adores her.
However,
she is unusually
close to Shen Run.
If she marries into the marquis's family,
I'm afraid Chunzhi will have to
endure a lifetime of humiliation.
Qingru is different.
They've been close
since they were kids.
She's the one who truly cares about Chunzhi.
If a principal wife
is devoted to the patriarch,
the family will
surely prosper.
My elder brother happens to be visiting too.
He can attend his niece's wedding.
Wouldn't that be wonderful?
Commissioner Hu is coming too?
There's still time before the marriage deed is sent
to the Ministry of Rites.
It's a joyous occasion.
His Majesty agreed?
His Majesty is already aware of your meeting
with Yongjia County Lady.
He is willing to give you a chance.
You're truly resourceful.
It's only been a few days,
and you've reported my every move
to His Majesty.
Your alliance with Xie Shu to bring down Hu Xing
is what His Majesty wants to see,
so naturally, he hopes you will maintain
close ties with the Xie family.
I was ordered to
relay to you that
he's agreed to your request.
But I'm sure you know
what conditions are involved.
Whether you accept this favor
is entirely up to you.
My dear,
isn't my osmanthus wine good?
It's my favorite too.
Once you're married,
you won't really
have a chance to visit anymore.
My baby.
Come on.
I'll drink a little with you.
Don't drink too much.
Silly child.
That's not how you drink wine.
Slow down.
Granny.
I'm just happy.
I'm getting married tomorrow.
Aren't you happy for me?
Knowing that you'll have good days ahead,
how could I not be?
Don't think I don't know
what you're really thinking.
You're marrying into the marquis's family
not for the heir
but for your mother.
You are
getting married tomorrow.
I shouldn't say anything more.
It's just...
I know full well that
this is the price I have to pay
to seek justice,
but this price...
is really too heavy.
Granny,
did I choose the wrong path
and make the wrong choice?
Silly girl.
It's okay.
Most people
start out not knowing what
they really want.
Later, as they move along,
they fall and cry,
and think they
took the wrong path.
In the end,
looking back,
they realize
everything was arranged
by heaven long ago,
so we can get what we wish for.
It's okay.
But I can't let go.
Granny,
I really can't let go.
It's okay.
I know.
Why are you here?
Did you drink?
Why didn't I know you can drink?
Get out of my way.
What?
Did you have to drink to drown your sorrows
when it's your wedding day tomorrow?
I'm happy.
You're lying.
I'm not lying.
I'm beyond happy.
And what about that?
♪ You, tender yet sharp, with thorns by your side ♪
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
♪ The wind and rain sigh, the road stretches far ♪
What do you want?
♪ Blossoms drift with streams, affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion; one cup of spring awakes me ♪
How could you say you're happy
to marry another man to my face?
♪ Burned and released, held by fate's hand ♪
Is it wrong to be happy?
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze and homebound sail to land ♪
When you were with the county lady,
you seemed pretty happy too.
♪ Slim moonbeams weave tangled dreams all night ♪
What exactly do you want?
♪ The homeward boat glides slowly through dark twilight ♪
I want to marry you.
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring fades to lingering cheer ♪
♪ You, tender yet sharp, with thorns by your side ♪
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
♪ The wind and rain sigh, the road stretches far ♪
♪ Blossoms drift with streams, affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion; one cup of spring awakes me ♪
♪ Burned and released, held by fate's hand ♪
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze and homebound sail to land ♪
♪ Slim moonbeams weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ The homeward boat glides slowly through dark twilight ♪
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring fades to lingering cheer ♪
My Lady,
have you really thought it through?
If you've changed your mind,
we can help you.
Are you really ready to
throw away your life
for revenge?
You clearly like Shen Run—
My mind is made up.
Stop dissuading me.
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
♪ Through the courtyard, pear blossoms flutter like snowflakes in a song ♪
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
I'll give you one last chance.
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
Wait for me.
I'll make your wish come true.
How long do I have to wait?
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
I won't make you wait long.
I can't wait.
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
It's now or never.
This is the last chance.
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
The auspicious hour has arrived!
Lift the sedan.
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
Hit the road!
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
My biggest dream in life
is to become Chunzhi's wife.
But now he's marrying someone else!
What's the point of living?
Mother,
I don't want to live anymore!
Just have a good cry.
I told you that
I can protect you for a while,
but I can't protect you forever.
You'll have to
shoulder many things on your own.
There is no rush.
Well,
the wheel of fortune is still turning.
I don't want to hear these abstract lectures.
He's about to marry someone else.
What else can I do?
They have yet to
tie the knot, have they?
Bearers?
Yesterday, I dreamed
of the first time I met you, Qingyuan,
and today you're my bride.
Am I still dreaming?
Who sent you?
Do you know who I am?
If you hurt me,
none of you will leave Hengtang alive!
How much were you paid?
I'll pay double.
Miss,
you've already seen our faces.
No amount of money
can save your life.
Just accept your fate and be on your way.
Shen...
Shen Che?
Thanks for saving me.
Did...
Shen Run send you?
You're marrying someone else
and still expect my brother to save you?
I didn't come to save you.
I came because I was worried
you'd forget the way to the marquis's residence
and miss the auspicious hour.
You want to make sure my wedding goes smoothly
so Shen Run can move on from me, right?
That's right.
If I kill you,
he'll just pine for you for the rest of his life.
Only when you become someone else's wife
will he truly move on.
He made his choice long ago,
and I have my own path to walk.
Our paths are different,
so we must part ways.
You don't need to force me.
I was on my way
to the wedding anyway.
The bride has arrived!
Walk upon the carpet squares!
Verdant grass drenched in rain and dew!
May every step bring blessings,
and a noble path
lead to endless grace!
Step over the saddle!
May you enjoy
peace year after year,
and grow old together
in lifelong health and peace!
Scatter the five grains!
May the five grains fill your granaries,
and blessings overflow the universe!
May your family be auspicious,
and your lineage flourish for generations!
Bow to heaven and earth!
First bow to heaven and earth!
Bow!
They have yet to tie the knot, have they?
Bring it here.
This...
This is...
I told you
your marriage is
more important than my life.
Second bow to the parents!
Bow!
Husband and wife, bow to each other!
The ceremony is complete!
Bravo! Bravo!
Congratulations!
-Bravo! -Congratulations!
Have a long and happy life together!
Qingyuan.
From now on,
you are my wife.
Wait a minute!
Why did you start
without the bride?
Qingyuan?
Who's under the veil then?
An impostor?
My son,
I...
I'll go check on Qingru.
Qingyuan!
I apologize, Young Master Li.
Courtesy of someone else,
I'm a little late.
Come with me!
Father,
from beginning to end,
the one I want to marry
is Xie Qingyuan.
She's here now.
Let's redo the wedding rites!
You're out of line!
Since you've performed the wedding rites
with Second Lady Xie,
the two of you are
husband and wife for life!
Everyone here's a witness.
This isn't playing house!
Lord Xie,
we agreed on a marriage with Fourth Lady.
Why did it become Second Lady?
Did we agree on Fourth Lady?
Cut the crap!
Second Lady is the one
Madam Li and I have been talking about all along.
Weren't you aware, Your Lordship?
No, I wasn't!
When my elder brother arrives,
Madam Li and I will give you
a proper explanation, Your Lordship.
When will Commissioner Hu arrive?
My brother said
he couldn't miss his niece's wedding banquet.
Then how should we handle
this situation?
Calm down, Your Lordship.
Take a seat.
Li.
Don't touch me!
The marquis is right.
The ceremony is complete
and cannot be undone.
I don't care about the ceremony!
I've sworn to marry Xie Qingyuan.
I'll give up my position as Marquis of Danyang's heir
before I yield.
Young Master Li.
Your Lordship,
since things have come to this,
I have a suggestion which
both fulfills Young Master Li's wish
and brings our two families closer.
Why don't Young Master Li
take Qingyuan as a concubine today?
Wouldn't that be a double blessing?
No!
My pledge to marry
Qingyuan as my wife
is set in stone.
Young Master Li,
you should give it some serious thought.
Qingyuan crashed the wedding hall
in her wedding dress
after you completed the ceremony.
This act brings disgrace to our family
and violates moral principles.
If you don't take her as a concubine,
the Xie household
cannot keep her either.
We'll have no choice
but to send her to a nunnery outside the city
to become a nun.
For the rest of her life, she'll never be able to
step out of those nunnery gates.
But if you take her as a concubine,
wouldn't you be able to protect her?
Can you really bear to see her end up
in such a place of hardship?
Your Lordship,
this matter cannot be delayed.
If word gets out,
it'll be disastrous for both our families.
By then,
we won't be able to help her
even if we want to.
Your Lordship,
what do you think?
My child,
do you really have the heart
to drive Qingyuan into a corner?
If you truly care for her, you should know
which is more important:
the title of wife
or the rest of her life.
Qingyuan.
I...
I don't want to see you suffer.
But I...
That day at the snack shop,
you swore to heaven that
you'd marry only me as your wife
and never take a concubine.
I thought you were
different from other men
who take multiple wives and concubines,
causing unrest in the household.
No,
I...
Young Master Li,
I know
you didn't mean to
break your promise.
But since you're already married,
it means we're not meant to be.
You don't need to insist on marrying me anymore.
Enough, Qingyuan.
Stop being unreasonable, okay?
Marriage is decided by the parents
and arranged by a matchmaker.
There's no room for private betrothals!
Young Master Li's feelings for you are sincere.
Instead of being grateful,
why are you being so aggressive?
That day,
I only agreed to the marriage because the heir swore
to marry me as his wife.
Now,
I've kept my promise,
but he married someone else.
I just want to cancel the engagement.
How's that being aggressive?
Fine.
My Lord and Your Lordship,
please make the decision.
Li.
It's decided.
After a discussion with Li,
we'll do
as you proposed.
What a brilliant idea,
My Lady.
Good things come in pairs, don't they?
Let auspiciousness beget auspiciousness.
As the saying goes,
there's no time like the present.
This is a foolproof plan.
Qingyuan,
do as we say.
If you don't marry into the marquis's family today,
in the future,
who would dare to marry you?
Yes.
So what if no one marries me?
I can live well
on my own.
I'd rather spend the remainder of my life in monastic seclusion
than submit to being a concubine!